Guide to the Richard C. Burns archive of Overtone Records, Inc.
Yale University Music Library
Richard C. Burns archive of Overtone Records, Inc.
1930-2001
1948-1990
MSS 104
Yale University Music Library
23.5
(30 boxes)
This archive documents the activities of Overtone Records, Inc., and its founder Richard C. Burns, through tape recorded material used for the publication of Overtone LPs; recordings of numerous live performances at Yale University, in the greater New Haven and Hartford, Connecticut, areas, and out of state; and through administrative files and background material used to support the operations of Overtone Records and various recording projects by Richard C. Burns.
Burns, Richard C., 1920-2002
Overtone Records, Inc.
Scope and Contents
This archive documents a period of revitalized interest in baroque music during the 1950s at Yale University, as well as certain aspects of twentieth century music, through sound recordings and administrative records. All seventeen issues of Overtone Records are represented through reel to reel master and copy tape recordings, including music by J.S. Bach, Alessandro Scarlatti, Dietrich Buxtehude--and several other Renaissance and Baroque composers--as well as works by twentieth century composers such as Charles Ives, Igor Stravinsky, Paul Hindemith, and Quincy Porter. Many performers featured on Overtone Records were members of the Yale faculty at the time, or in some way associated with the Yale community, such as composer, conductor, and early music enthusiast Paul Hindemith, cellist Aldo Parisot, organist Luther Noss, violinist and conductor Howard Boatwright, soprano Helen Boatwright, harpsichordist Albert Fuller, pianist John Kirkpatrick, the Choir of St. Thomas's Episcopal Church (New Haven, Connecticut), and others.
Other recordings document special projects by Richard C. Burns, mostly in the New Haven and Hartford, Connecticut, areas, of Evensong church services; American Guild of Organist seminars and conferences; New Haven Chorale performances; the annual Spring Choral Festival of Secondary Schools; works performed by the Choir of St. Thomas's Episcopal Church; the Albertus Magnus and Yale Divinity choirs; compositions by Paul Hindemith and Howard Boatwright; concerts by the Yale Whiffenpoofs and Alley Cats; performances by the Yale Collegium Musicum (founded and conducted by Paul Hindemith); and events and concerts involving other individuals, ensembles, and organizations. Some projects were remastered and transferred onto DAT tapes, including mono to stereo updates.
Administrative files document the organizational operations of Overtone Records, Inc., as well as special projects, through correspondence, contracts, reviews, discographies, articles, promotional drafts, and other routine business transaction receipts.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series: I. Administrative records, II. Background materials, III. Overtone recordings, IV. Richard C. Burns recording projects, and V. Overtone and Richard C. Burns digitized and remastered recordings.
Biographical Sketch of Richard C. Burns
Richard C. Burns was born in 1920 and raised in New Haven,Connecticut. His interest in classical music developed in his teens when he would listen to live radio broadcasts of the Metropolitan Opera and other performances. Burns graduated from Yale University in 1942 with a degree in physics. He worked for a yearafter graduation at the Bureau of Standards, Washington DC, and then worked as a recording engineer for Soundscriber Corporation in New Haven. He began volunteering as a project recording engineer for various New Haven musical performances and church services in 1949. In the 1950s Burns began doing recording projects for Yale composer and faculty member Paul Hindemith, who also founded and was music director of the Yale Collegium Musicum. Burns then founded Overtone Records, Inc., in 1953 and served as the company's producer and recording engineer. In 1966 he was appointed audio engineer at Syracuse University by colleague Howard Boatwright, for whom he had made several recordings in New Haven. Burns remained in Syracuse University until 1984. He also collaborated with recording engineer Tom Packard to invent and manufacture the Packburn, an analogue machine that reduces surface noise on 78-rpm and LP Recordings. Burns died in 2002.
Administrative History of Overtone Records, Inc.
Overtone Records, Inc.,was founded in 1953 by Richard C. Burns, who served as the company's producer and sound engineer. Overtone published seventeen LP recording. The repertoire on the recordings primarily consists of baroque music, but also includes works from the Renaissanceera, as well as nineteenth and twentieth century music. Overtone's recording of The Passion according to St. Johnby Alessandro Scarlatti won the Grand Prix du Disque at its French release. Featured artists on these recordings include Paul Hindemith, Luther Noss, Albert Fuller, Helen Boatwright, John Kirkpatrick, Aldo Parisot, and Howard Boatwright; and the ensembles recorded include the Yale Collegium Musicum, Yale Divinity Choir, the Choir of St. Thomas's Episcopal Church (New Haven), and members of the Yale University Orchestra.
During the production of the seventeen Overtone recordings and in the years following, Burns engaged in several recording projects, mostly live events, that were loosely associated with Overtone Records and documented in the same administrative files (some recording numbers included the OV designation). Most of these projects were not released commercially.
Conditions Governing Access
The original audiovisual materials in this collection cannot not be played onsite at Yale. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy to be made. All copies are provided as digital files. Digital transfers are conducted by third party preservation vendors that are contracted to digitize Historical Sound Recordings (HSR) collection materials. If the materials requested are already available digitally, you will be contacted with an offer to stream the recordings for 30 days, free of charge. Consult the HSR website for more information on requesting digital copies.
Collegium musicum (Yale University); Glee clubs; Orchestral music; Choruses; Audiocassettes; open reel audiotapes; Music -- 17th century; Music -- 18th century; St. Thomas Episcopal Church (New Haven, Conn.). Choir; Burns, Richard C., 1920-2002; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Boatwright, Howard, 1918-1999; Boatwright, Helen; Yale University. Yale Glee Club; Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966; Hickok, Robert; Overtone Records, Inc.
- Administrative records, Series I
  - Accounts receivable, 1971–1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Unpaid records.
  - Advertisement reproductions, 1955–1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advertisers, 1957–1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Advertisers, 1963-1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Advertisers, 1971-1976, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Advertising ideas and layout, 1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Analysis of sales, 1956–1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Articles: Miscellaneous, circa 1969-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Audio Engineering Society reprints, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Audiophile magazines, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Boatwright, Helen, 1965–1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Includes letters from Howard Boatwright.
  - Boatwright, Howard and Helen, 1943, 1953-1956 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Publicity.
  - British Broadcasting Corporation, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Paul Hindemith conducting Bach motets.
  - Busch, Adolf and Fritz, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Discographies.
  - Conductors, photographs of, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Consorti Della Musica, circa 1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Includes photograph of Helen Boatwright and others.
  - Contracts: American Federation of Musicians, 1952–1954 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Contracts: Artists, 1953–1958 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Includes Paul Hindemith.
  - Contracts: Composers Recordings Inc. (CRI), 1994–1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Contracts: Distributors, 1954–1964 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Contracts: Miscellaneous, 1953–1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Contracts: Music performance trust fund, 1948–1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    Trust agreement.
  - Contracts: Publishers, 1955–1958 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Copyright license request and processing request, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
    Blank forms.
  - Cost of records, 1953–1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Cost of records, 1954–1970 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Fox, Harry, 1955–1969 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - G. Schirmer, Inc., 1955–1973 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - History and technology of recordings, 1969–1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    Articles.
  - Inventory and capital assets, 1954–1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Ives, Charles, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    Discography survey by David Hall, in three parts.
  - Ives Records, 1954–1955 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    Copyright issues.
  - Ives Records, 1956-1965, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    Contains correspondence, programs, and promotional material.
  - Leeds Music Corporation, 1953–1956 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Lumen Records, 1957–1958 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Macmillan Company, 1966–1969 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Marvin, Frederick, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    Reviews of recordings.
  - Mechanical Instruments, 1965-1967, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    Contains articles and music.
  - Music performance trust fund, 1951–1969 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - NMQR Records, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Noss, Luther, 1954-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Noss, Luther, 1954–1974 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Royalties on record #3.
  - Organs and organists, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    Photographs.
  - Porter, Quincy, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    Contains article and review from the American Composers' Alliance Bulletin.
  - Purchase orders, 1975-1976, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Radio Corporation of America, 1962–1967 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    Correspondence.
  - Radio Corporation of America, 1963–1967 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    Financial records.
  - Record mastering form and record production contract, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Record publicity: Other, 1954–1984 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Record reviews, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Recording contracts and forms, circa 1960 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    Overtone Records.
  - Reviewers: Communication to and from, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Reviewers: Communication to and from, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Reviews: Buxtehude, Dietrich - Two cantatas, 1954–1955 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    Recording no. 6.
  - Reviews: Christmas music from Trinity, New Haven, 1956–1959 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    Recording no. 11.
  - Reviews: Fuller, Albert - Gaspard Le Roux, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    Recording no. 15.
  - Reviews: Ives, Charles - Twenty-four Songs, 1955, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    Recording no. 7.
  - Reviews: Marvin, Frederick, 1977–1978 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Reviews: Noss, Luther - Baroque organ music, 1957–1958 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    Recording no. 12.
  - Reviews: Noss, Luther - Baroque organ works, 1955–1956 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    Recording no. 8.
  - Reviews: Organ works, 1957–1961 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    Recording nos. 13 and 14.
  - Reviews: Parisot, Aldo, 1958, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    Recording nos. 16 and 17.
  - Reviews, 1954-1955, undated (Box 5, Folder 64)
    Paste-ups and originals.
  - Reviews: Porter, Quincy, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    Recording no. 10.
  - Reviews: Rosenmueller, Johann, 1956–1957 (Box 5, Folder 66)
    Recording no. 9.
  - Reviews: Scarlatti, Alessandro - Passion According to St. John, 1954-1960, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 67)
    Recording no. 1. Also includes Blake Stern's obituary.
  - Reviews: Scheidt, Samuel, 1954–1955 (Box 5, Folder 68)
    Recording no. 3.
  - Reviews: Yale Collegium Musicum, 1955–1958 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    Recordings nos. 4-5 with Paul Hindemith as conductor.
  - Reviews: Yale Divinity School Choir, 1954-1958, undated (Box 5, Folder 70)
    Recording no. 2.
  - Romantic Organ Music Symposium, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Rosenmueller recording - Overtone no. 9, 1955–1958 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - St. Thomas' Choir: Publicity, 1953–1957 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - St. Thomas' Choir: Spring music festival, 1955–1957 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - Schedule of payments and equipment checklist, circa 1964-1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - Sesac, Inc., 1953–1966 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - Sheet music, undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - Utilities, 1953–1990 (Box 6, Folder 78)
    Includes articles mostly from The Gramophone.
  - Warren, Richard, 1960–1961 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - Warren, Richard, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Warren, Richard, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Warren, Richard, 1967–1971 (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Warren, Richard, 1972–1974 (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Warren, Richard, 1975–1980 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Warren, Richard, 1981–1987 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Warren, Richard, 1998–2001 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - White, Edward, 1957–1964 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    Envelope specialists.
  - Yale Historical Sound Recordings Project, 1987–1994 (Box 7, Folder 88)
- Background materials, Series II
  - Articles and miscellaneous background information, 1967–1976 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - "The Bel Canto", undated (Box 8, Folder 90)
    Talk notes and music annotated to reflect historical recordings.
  - Discography Series I: Schubert lieder (revised), undated (Box 8, Folder 91)
  - Discography Series II: Wolf, Hugo, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 92)
  - Discography Series III & IV: Schumann and Brahms lieder, 1970–1971 (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Discography Series V: Schubert, Schumann, and Brahms choral music, undated (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Discography Series VI: Mendelssohn Vocal Music, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Discography Series VII: Strauss, Richard - Llieder, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Discography Series IX: Mahler, Gustav, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Discography Series X: Bruckner, Anton, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Discography Series XI: Debussy and Ravel vocal music, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Discography Series XII: Varese, Edgard, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Discography Series XIII: Bernstein, Leonard, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 101)
  - Discography Series XIV: Berg, Alban, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 102)
  - Discography Series XV: Pfitzner and Marx, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 103)
  - Discography Series XVI: Britten, Benjamin, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 104)
  - Discography Series XVII: Strauss, Richard - Opera, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 105)
  - Discography Series XVIII: Janacek, Leos, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 106)
  - The Gramophone Record, by H. Courtney Bryson, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 107)
  - "The Mechanical Reproduction of Sound", 1990 (Box 9, Folder 108)
    Talk by Richard C. Burns. Includes sound improvement patent specification.
  - Numerical lists of Victor and Columbia albums, undated (Box 9, Folder 109)
  - Organ, circa 1911-1975 (Box 9, Folder 110)
    Notes, talks, and related correspondence.
  - Organ, 1973–1975 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Piano playing and pianists, 1972-1982, undated (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - "Portamento," by Edward William Brombach, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 113)
    With introductory marks by Richard C. Burns [?].
  - Record listings, annotated, undated (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - String playing and string players, 1931-1975, undated (Box 10, Folder 115)
- Overtone recordings, Series III
  - Overtone no. 1 (OV 1), 1953
    Alessandro Scarlatti: The Passion According to St. John; Blake Stern, Evangelist; David Laurent, Christ. Members of the Yale University Orchestra, The Choir of St. Thomas' Episcopal Church, Howard Boatwright, conductor. Recorded 1953 Mar-Apr.
    - Side A, 1962 September 9 (Box 11, Item 1)
      Copy.
    - Side B, 1962 September 9 (Box 11, Item 2)
    - Reel 2, circa 1962 (Box 11, Item 3)
    - Disc 1, side A, 1962 September 28 (Box 11, Item 4)
      Includes musical and technical information in and on storage case.
    - Disc 1, side B, 1962 September 8 (Box 11, Item 5)
  - Overtone no. 2 (OV 2), 1952
    The Divinity School Choir, Yale University: Selections from the repertory, 1951-1952, including J.S. Bach: Now let every tongue adore Thee; William Billings: Wake every breath; Sergei Rachmaninoff: Glory be to God; Virgil Thompson: Psalms 123 and 136. Jim Borden, director. Recorded 1952 May.
    - Side A, 1966 April 13 (Box 11, Item 6)
    - Side B, 1966 April 13 (Box 11, Item 7)
  - Overtone no. 3 (OV 3), 1953
    Samuel Scheidt: Selections from Tabulatura; Chorale variations on Warem betrübst du dich, mein Herz? Da Jesus an dem Kreuze stund; Magnificat noni Toni, Mudus ludendi pleno Organa pedaliter; Variations on "Est-ce-Mars?" Luther Noss, organ. Recorded 1953.
    - Side A (Box 11, Item 8)
    - Side B (Box 11, Item 9)
    - Side A (Box 11, Item 10)
      Mylar copy.
    - Side B (Box 11, Item 11)
    - Side A (Box 11, Item 12)
      2nd copy.
    - Side B (Box 11, Item 13)
  - Overtone no. 4 (OV 4), 1953 May 14
    Collegium Musicum of Yale University School of Music, vol. 1: Claudio Monteverdi: Lagrime d'amante al sepolcro dell'amata, and other choral works by Thomas Weelkes, Carlo Gesualdo, Johann Sebastian Bach, et al. Paul Hindemith, conductor. Recorded 1953 May 14.
    - Reel 1, side A, E4-KP-1392, 1961 September 23 (Box 11, Item 14)
    - Reel 2, side B, E4-KP-1393, 1961 (Box 11, Item 15)
    - Equalized master (1) (Box 11, Item 16)
    - Equalized master (2) (Box 11, Item 17)
  - Overtone no. 5 (OV 5), 1951 May 20
    Collegium Musicum of Yale University School of Music, vol. 2: Choral works by Orlando Di Lasso, Jacob Handl, Giovanni Gabrieli, G.P. da Palestrina et al. Paul Hindemith, conductor. Recorded 1951 May 20.
    - H8-OP-9733 (Box 11, Item 18)
    - Side B, equalized master, H8-OP-9734 (Box 11, Item 19)
  - Overtone no. 6 (OV 6), 1953
    Dietrich Buxtehude: Herr, auf Dich freue ich; Singet dem Herrn; Laude Sion Salvatorem; Jesu, meine Freude. Helen Boatwright, soprano, choir of St. Thomas' Episcopla Church, Howard Boatwright, conductor. Recorded 1953 Nov - Dec.
    - Side A, E4-KP-3568 (Box 12, Item 20)
      Includes technical information in storage case.
    - Side B, E4-KP-3569, 1956 (Box 12, Item 21)
    - Side A, 1956 December 15 (Box 12, Item 22)
      Mylar copy. Includes technical information in storage case.
    - Side B, 1956 December 15 (Box 12, Item 23)
  - Overtone no. 7 (OV 7), 1954
    Charles Ives: Twenty-four Songs. Helen Boatwright, soprano, and John Kirkpatrick, piano. Recorded 1954 Aug.
    - Side A (Box 12, Item 24)
      Copy. Includes technical information in storage case.
    - Side B (Box 12, Item 25)
    - Side A (Box 12, Item 26)
    - Side B (Box 12, Item 27)
    - D copies disc 7 -- Sides A [?] and B (Box 12, Item 28)
    - F8-OP-0409-1 master (Box 12, Item 29)
    - F8-OP-0407-2 master, 1956 (Box 12, Item 30)
    - F8-OP-0406-1 master (Box 12, Item 31)
  - Overtone no. 8 (OV 8), 1954
    Various organ works, including Johann Pachelbel: Toccata in C major, Tocatta in F major; and works by Johann Gottfried Walther. Luther Noss, organ. Recorded 1954.
    - Originals of Toccata in C major and Toccata in F major, and Warum betrübst du dich, mein Herz [?] (Box 12, Item 32)
    - C -- Side A (Box 12, Item 33)
    - D -- Side A (Box 12, Item 34)
    - Side A (Box 12, Item 35)
      Mylar copy. AME curve.
    - Side B (Box 12, Item 36)
    - Side A, F8-OP-0408-1 master, 1961 September 6 (Box 12, Item 37)
      Includes musical and technical information in storage case.
  - Overtone no. 9 (OV 9), 1855
    Various vocal/choral works by Johann Rosenmüller. Helen Boatwright, soprano, choir of St. Thomas' Episcopal Church, Howard Boatwright, conductor. 1855 May, Aug - Sep.
    - Reel 1, G8-OP-7534-(M) (Box 13, Item 38)
    - Reel 2, G8-OP-7535 (M) (Box 13, Item 39)
      Nunc Dimittis.
    - Reel 1 (Box 13, Item 40)
    - Reel 2 (Box 13, Item 41)
    - Side A, 1989 March 3 (Box 13, Item 42)
      Copy. Includes technical information in storage case apparently written on 1989 Mar 3.
    - Side B (Box 13, Item 43)
  - Overtone no. 10 (OV 10), 1955
    Quincy Porter: Symphony no. 1, Dance in Three time, Concerto Concertante for Two Pianos and Orchestra. André Terrasse and Jean-Léon Cohen, pianos, Orchestre des Concerts Colonne, Quincy Porter, conductor. Recorded 1955 Jun.
    - Side A, 1962 March 7 (Box 13, Item 44)
    - Side B, 1962 March 7 (Box 13, Item 45)
  - Overtone no. 11 (OV 11), 1954–1955
    Christmas Music from Trinity New Haven; The Choir of Men and Boys of Trinity Parish. G. Huntington Byles, organ and choirmaster. Recorded 1954-1955 (Winter).
    - A, 1964 December 8 (Box 13, Item 46)
      Copy. Includes technical information on storage case.
    - B, 1964 December 8 (Box 13, Item 47)
  - Overtone no. 12 (OV 12), 1956
    Various organ works by Dietrich Buxtehude and Georg Böhm. Luther Noss, organ. Recorded 1956.
    - Side A (Box 13, Item 48)
    - Side B (Box 13, Item 49)
    - Side A (Mylar) (Box 13, Item 50)
    - Side B (Mylar) (Box 13, Item 51)
    - Side A, G8-OP-8838 (Box 13, Item 52)
    - Side B, G8-OP-8839 (Box 13, Item 53)
  - Overtone no. 13 (OV 13), 1955
    Various organ works, inlcuding Johann Sebastian Bach: Nun Konm' der Heiden Heiland (BWV 659), Wir glauben All' an einem Gott (BWV 680), Prelude and Fugue in E-flat, Toccata and Fugue in D minor and F major; Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart: Fantasia in F major, KV 608, Adagio and Allegro in F major, KV 594; Marcel Dupré, playing the Cavaillé-Coll organ of Saint-Sulpice, Paris, France. Recorded 1955 Nov. Contains some material duplicated in OV 14.
    - Side A (Box 13, Item 54)
      Incudes musical and technical information in storage case.
    - Side B (Box 13, Item 55)
    - Side A, equalized master, H8-OP-5247 (Box 13, Item 56)
    - Side B, equalized master, H8-OP-5248 (Box 13, Item 57)
    - Side A, equalized master (Box 14, Item 58)
    - Side B, equalized master (Box 14, Item 59)
  - Overtone no. 14 (OV 14), 1955
    Various organ works, including Johann Sebastian Bach: Prelude and Fugue in E-flat major (BWV 552); Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart: Fantasia in F major, KV 608, Adagio and Alllegro in F minor, KV 594, Marcel Dupré, playing the Cavaillé-Coll organ of Saint-Sulice, Paris, France. Recorded 1955 Nov.
    - Side A (Box 14, Item 60)
    - Side B, original (Box 14, Item 61)
    - Side A, equalized master, H8-OP-5249 (Box 14, Item 62)
    - Side B, equalized master, H8-OP-5250 (Box 14, Item 63)
    - Side B, equalized master (Box 14, Item 64)
      Second time.
  - Overtone no. 15 (OV 15), 1957
    Gaspard Le Roux: various harpsichord works. Albert Fuller, harpsichord. Recorded 1957.
    - J8-OP-1773 (Box 14, Item 65)
    - J8-OP-1174 (Box 14, Item 66)
    - Side A (Box 14, Item 67)
    - Side B (Box 14, Item 68)
    - Side A (Box 14, Item 69)
    - Side B (Box 14, Item 70)
  - Overtone no. 16 (OV 16), circa 1956
    Various works for cello and piano: Felix Mendelssohn: Sonata no. 2 in D major, Op. 58; Claude Debussy: Sonata no. 1 in D minor; Robert Schumann: Fantasiestücke, Op. 73. Aldo Parisot, cello, and Leopold Mittman, piano. Recorded 1956 or 1957.
    - Side A, 1966 April 14 (Box 14, Item 71)
      Copy. 15/AME on Scotch #202 (Mylar).
    - Side B, 1966 April 14 (Box 14, Item 72)
      Copy, 15/AME on Scotch #202 (Mylar).
  - Overtone no. 167 (OV 17), circa 1956
    Various works for cello and piano -- Felix Mendelssohn: Variations Concertante, Op. 17; Franz Schubert: "Arpeggione" sonata in A minor; Frédéric Chopin: Sonata in G minor, Op. 65. Aldo Parisot, cello, and Leopold Mittman, piano. Recorded 1956 or 1957.
    - J8-OP-1777 (Box 14, Item 73)
    - J8-OP-1778 (Box 14, Item 74)
    - Side A (Box 14, Item 75)
    - Side B (Box 14, Item 76)
    - Side A (Box 15, Item 77)
    - Side B (Box 15, Item 78)
- Richard C. Burns recording projects, Series IV
  - Goon Show (OV-S-115), 1968 (Box 15, Item 79)
  - Albertus Magnus Choir (OV-109), undated
    - Side A (Box 15, Item 80)